布朗克斯区 朗费罗动物医院
--=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 兜来兜去
时间轴:  sharefans_竺
翻译: 初见 伊娃  sharefans_竺 nikifa
校对: 失眠影 飞天宇
这是哪里?
Where are we?
飞机上
The plane.
什么飞机?
What?
Udinov家族的慷慨赠送
Courtesy of the Udinov family trust.
我们可以把这里当成指挥部
We've been using it as our command center.
你怎么...
How did you...
你没来约定的地方
When you didn't show at the rendezvous point,
我就回头找你 在车祸现场发现了你的踪迹
I backtracked and picked up your trail from the crash.
子弹直接穿了过去 但是你失血过多
It's through and through, but you lost a lot of blood.
可能会有点晕
You're gonna feel faint.
为了处理伤口 我把你的衣服剪掉了
I had to cut your shirt off to get to the wound.
要是她醒了 我...
If she's awake, I need to...
不 让她休息一下
No, let's let her rest.
- Nikki  - 呆子
- Nikki.  - Nerd.
嘿
Hey.
我真怕再也见不到你了
Wasn't sure we'd see you alive again.
还好你没事
Glad we did.
这里还有别人吗?
Who else is here?
没有了 就我们
Right now, this is it.
- 谁开的飞机?  - 自动驾驶
- Who's flying the plane?  - Autopilot.
我们现在正要去华盛顿
Right now, we're halfway to D.C.
为什么?
Why?
你应该看看这个
There's something you should see.
现已确定 正是刺杀了总统的刺客
At this point, I can confirm that presidential assassin
Nikita Mears策划了这场爆炸
Nikita Mears was the individual who planted the explosive device
导致ENN记者Dale Gordon的死亡
resulting in the death of ENN journalist Dale Gordon.
同时 我们已经确定了
We also believe that we have uncovered
她的动机
the motive for the killing.
根据他的调查笔记
According to his notes, Mr. Gordon was set
Gordon先生正在调查一个海外账户
to report on evidence of an offshore cayman account
据国安局称 那个账户是Nikita Mears名下的
that, according to NSA, was in Nikita Mears's name.
一派胡言
That's a lie.
一定是Graham杀了Dale之后
Graham must have planted that evidence on Dale
又把笔记本放在他身上
right after he killed him.
是我让Dale直接去找联邦调查局局长的
I told Dale to go straight to the head of the FBI.
- 是我害了他  - 不
- I'm the reason he's dead.  - No.
Amanda才是凶手
He's dead because of Amanda.
她控制着Graham
She's the one controlling Graham.
但她怎么做到的?
Yeah, but how? How is she doing this?
- 她怎么做到这一切的?  - 我想我知道了
- How is she doing any of this?  - I think I know.
联邦调查局的副局长
The Deputy Director of the FBI,
德国情报局官员 机密行动指挥官
a German BND officer, a secret service supervisor,
还有美国总统
and the President of the United States.
他们都是高层领导人
All high level.
不可能被收买
All seemingly incorruptible,
但却都叛国了 为什么?
yet all clearly compromised. how?
Amanda可以给他们下药
Well, if Amanda drugged them,
然后让他们坐上手术椅
she could have gotten them in her chair,
给他们的脑袋来一针?
stuck her needle in their heads?
Amanda的手术需要几个小时
Amanda's needling takes several hours,
最少也得半天
half a day at least.
如果这些人消失这么长时间
Any of these people disappear for that long,
一定会有人察觉的
they would have been noticed.
那她是怎么给他们洗脑的?
So how did she brainwash them?
不是洗脑 是掉包
She didn't. she switched them.
掉包?
Switched?
复制品
A double.
完美的替代
A perfect replica.
他们在身体上和精神上
Someone who's been physically
都与被复制者完全一样
and mentally altered to act as a replacement.
哦... Ryan
Uh... look, Ryan, I know
我知道你是个阴谋论者
you're the conspiracy guy and everything,
- 但这也太...  - 让人难以置信?
- but all this sounds a little...  - Hard to believe?
如果不知道已经有这种技术了
It would be, if we didn't know
确实可能不会相信
the Shop already had the tech for it.
高分子聚合物可以复制出人脸
Polymers that can make copies of someone's face,
DNA可以分化出身体各器官
body parts regenerated from source DNA,
再加上Amanda的一点技术
and now, Amanda is working with them.
她可以向人脑里移植芯片
She can install psychic circuit breakers into a person's head,
让他们忠心耿耿
make subjects suggestible and loyal.
她就是这样让Sam变成了Owen
The way she turned Sam into Owen.
这些加在一块
Put it all together, and you got a system
她就有了完美的卧底计划
to create the perfect undercover operative.
他们和真身一模一样
They look and act exactly like the real thing,
就连最亲近的人也看不出来
enough to fool even the people closest to them.
把他们安插进去
Place in the right positions, these operatives
商会就能掌控无上权力
would give the Shop incredible access and power.
在Alex发现商会运送的四个巴基斯坦人
It came together for me after Alex intercepted
完全一样的时候... 我就明白了
the Shop's latest shipment... four Pakistani men,
他们长得一模一样
All the same physical type.
他们要找的不是普通奴隶
They're not looking for random slaves.
而是能够塑造成别人的
They're looking for a specific type of clay
复制品原料
to mold into a preexisting form.
她怎么发现的?
How did she find that out?
她在追踪人贩子
She's been chasing human traffickers,
特别是和商会有关系的那些
ones with connection to the Shop.
- 她单独行动的?  - 还有Sonya
- By herself?  - Sonya's with her.
她可是Alex
Anyway, it's Alex.
她知道怎么照顾自己的
She knows how to take care of herself.
你不是在海边度假吗?
Shouldn't you be on a beach somewhere,
像其他退休清理人一样晒着太阳
doing whatever retired cleaners do?
那多没劲 事实证明 那会让我长雀斑
It got boring. Turns out, I freckle.
印度 孟买
你偷了那么多钱
And you couldn't think of anything else to do
就不能干点别的吗?
with your stolen money?
偷? 那是我应得的
Stolen? I earned that money.
是Amanda对我洗脑
That's payback for ten whole years
整整十年的补偿
Amanda's brain rape stole from me.
三亿的补偿可真够多的
300 million is pretty good payback.
这只是个开始
It's a start.
你觉得无聊...
So you just got bored...
就来到孟买
decided to come to Mumbai
追捕人贩子了?
and hunt human traffickers?
不 我来到孟买
No. I decided to come to Mumbai
来抓那个想要抓人贩子的俄罗斯富二代
to hunt Russian heiresses who hunt human traffickers.
为什么?
Why?
因为有了你 我才能找到Amanda
'Cause you're my best shot at finding Amanda.
她把我像傻瓜一样耍
She made me look like a fool,
先是把我变成Owen
first by turning me into Owen,
然后在多伦多的G20峰会上让我出丑
then by playing me at the G20 back in Toronto.
我知道你们也在找她
I knew you guys would be looking for her too,
所以一直跟着你们
so I've been following you.
我看到你从他手下那里
I saw you take that scanner
拿到了一个扫描仪
off one of her operatives.
这是我在几个月里的第一条确凿线索
First solid lead I've seen in months,
你得把它给我
and you're gonna give it to me.
里面的数据
The data on this
能让我们找到陷害Nikita的人
could lead us to the people who framed Nikita.
- 它对我们很重要  - 你别无选择
- We need this.  - I'm not asking.
快走! 快走!
Go, go, go, go, go!
是人贩子 他们在找同伙
More traffickers, looking for their pals.
给我把枪!
Give me a gun!
Owen 快点!
Owen!
等等
他们逃不掉的
我本来是打算离开的
I was on my way out of here.
那辆车被遗弃在西面
The car was abandoned on the west side.
我们封锁了附近五十个街区
We've got a 50-block cordon around the area.
没用的 她已经逃走了
It won't matter. she's gone.
她受伤了 需要医治
She's wounded. she'll need medical attention.
她干了这么一票
After what she just pulled,
肯定很久不会再冒险
she won't stick her head up for anything,
她会低调行事
not for a very long time.
先生 你的电话 Nikita打来的
Sir, you've got a call. it's Nikita.
先生 这个电话
Sir, call's right here.
嘿! 小点声!
Hey! Keep it down!
接通她
Put her on.
我是Graham
This is Graham.
你把我耍了
You know, you really had me fooled,
你说你只要真相
saying you were looking for the truth.
我没想到你自己就是个骗局
I didn't realize you were hiding it about yourself.
你受伤了 赶紧自首
You're injured. turn yourself in.
我保证你会得到治疗的
I promise, you'll be taken care of.
就像你给Dale Gordon的治疗一样?
Oh, you mean the way you took care of Dale Gordon?
别伤及无辜
No one else has to get hurt.
我要揭露你的真实身份
I'm going to expose you for who you really are.
我不知道你有什么目的
I don't know what you hope to accomplish.
大家听好了 这个自称Graham副局长的人
To everyone listening in, the man claiming
是个冒牌货
to be Deputy Director Graham is an impostor.
你们肯定也发现了
I'm sure many of you have noticed
他最近有点不对劲
that he's been a little off.
有点行为异常
Lapses in routine.
你们都知道
Have any of you asked him
最近他给谁打私人电话了吗?
who he's been talking to on his private phone?
你听好了 我会找到你的
Listen to me. I am gonna find you.
你觉得你还能躲多久?
How long do you think you can keep running?
不 不 你没听明白我的话
No, no, no, I don't think you're hearing me.
我已经躲了三个月
I've been on the run for three months,
躲着你 躲着大家
from you, from my life.
我放弃了一切
I have given up everything
甚至不敢说真话 但现在不会了
for even a shred of the truth, and now I have it.
我不会再躲躲藏藏了
So I'm not chasing shadows anymore.
我已经知道怎么反击了
I have a point of attack.
你就是目标
You.
尼基塔 第四季第2集
有四个人
I count four.
- 在两个位置  - 他们在等我们出去
- Two cover positions.  - They're waiting us out.
也许在等待支援
Probably expecting reinforcements.
我们应该在支援到达之前出去
We should get out of here before they arrive.
我们得想办法到货车上
We need to make it to that van.
他们抢占了很好的位置 这是找死
With the cover they have? That'd be suicide.
Sonya 能听到吗?
Sonya, are you there?
Alex! 你怎么还没回来?
Alex! Why aren't you on your way back?
我被困住了
Got held up.
- 我们需要帮忙  - "你们"?
- We need your help.  - "We"?
- 我和Owen  - Owen?
- Me and Owen.  - Owen?
- 就是Sam  - 他怎么...
- I mean, Sam.  - What's he...
以后再说 我们被Priya的手下
Later. look, we got pinned down
困住了
by Priya's men.
我们需要掩护来突出重围
We need some sort of distraction to get past them.
我可以入侵电网
I think I can hack the power grid
关掉路灯
and shut down the lights.
- 这样足够了吗?  - 够了
- Will that give you enough cover?  - I think so.
我们得打掉车头灯
We need to take out the headlights.
好的 你负责左面
All right. you take the left,
我负责右面
I got the right.
我知道你想报仇
Look, I get it. you want vengeance.
Amanda那样对你
After what Amanda did to you,
我也会感同身受 所以我知道你的目的
I would feel the same way, so I get what you're doing.
但不代表我信任你
But that doesn't mean I trust you.
没关系 我也不信任你
That's okay. I don't trust you either.
我们在这点上是一致的
So we've got that in common.
Sonya 动手吧
Sonya, do it.
Alex啊!
Alex!
你对我开枪!
You shot me!
射在防弹衣上了
In the kevlar.
我把你推出了他的发射范围
I knocked you out of his line of fire.
你怎么知道我穿了防弹衣?
How did you know I had it on?
标准行动装备
Standard mission protocol.
你是那种严守规定的人
And you're the kind to keep to protocol.
也就是说你是瞎猜的
Meaning you guessed.
下次给我点提醒
Next time, give me a heads-up.
我叫"Alex"了
I said "Alex".
不 我... 我觉得没人会相信她
No, I... I don't think anyone believes her.
她也没指望
She didn't expect them to.
她打给你只是为了通知我
She called you to let me know
她重回游戏了
she's back in the game.
那我要进行阿尔法应急计划吗?
Do I proceed with alpha contingency?
不用了 她只是想逼你做出反应
No, she's trying to get you to react,
走进陷阱而已
force you into a false move.
你叫Matthew Graham
Your name is Matthew Graham.
你是联邦调查局的副局长
You're the Deputy Director of the FBI.
你要对政府 对国家 以及对我
You have a duty to your office and to your country
负责
and to me.
我们在执行重大的使命
This is important work we're doing.
Nikita活在聚光灯下好久了
Nikita's been living under the glare of the spotlight.
现在她觉得也许有办法
Now she thinks there may be a way
把这当成优势
to use it to her advantage.
好吧 我会保证继续让她成为焦点
Well, I'm going to make sure it stays on her.
终有一天把她烧焦
I'm going to make sure it sears her.
Amanda到底要利用
What's Amanda trying to do
这个秘密账户的谎做什么?
with this lie about the secret account?
铺设背景
Establish a context.
为Spencer的暗杀编故事
Create a narrative for Spencer's assassination.
没错 但为什么?
Yeah, but why?
我们以为杀了总统
We thought killing the President
商会的游戏就结束了
was the endgame for the Shop,
但可能那只是开始
but maybe it's just the beginning.
这不像Amanda的风格
This doesn't feel like Amanda.
太阴险了
It's too subtle.
另有其人
This is someone else.
他知道怎么在财政部门
Someone who knows how to maneuver
游刃自如
in the financial sector.
他以前掌握权势
Someone who's used to power
但也安于待在阴暗处
but comfortable staying in the shadows.
Nikita那边的电话
And no other voices could be heard
没听到其他声音吗?
on Nikita's side of the call?
没有 长官 声音取证也没结果
No, sir, audio forensics were inconclusive.
我以为联邦调查局有追踪信号
I'm assuming the FBI tried to trace the signal.
他们追踪了 但是没追到
They did, but without any success.
他们是怎么发现复制的?
How did they discover the double?
我们没留下蛛丝马迹
We left no loose ends.
事实证明Nikita掌握着很多资源
Nikita has proven to be very resourceful.
不 这超出她的能力范围了
No. No, this is beyond her.
要解决这样的问题...
Figuring out something like this is...
需要更抽象的思维
It's a much more abstract level of thought.
非对称
Asymmetrical.
对模式识别的独特天赋
A unique talent for pattern recognition.
是Ryan Fletcher
Ryan Fletcher.
抱歉
Sorry.
噢 伤口真糟糕
Ugh, that's gnarly.
原本有可能更糟
Could have been a lot worse.
你够幸运的 Mikey及时找到了你
You're lucky Mikey got to you when he did.
幸运
Lucky.
Dale Gordon就没那么幸运 对吧?
Not so much for Dale Gordon, huh?
每个人都被Graham骗了 你也不知道
Graham had everybody fooled. You couldn't have known.
对 但我把Dale也卷进来了
Yeah, but I'm the one who got Dale involved.
我老是犯错
I'm always the one.
当时我已经很小心了
You know, when I was out there, nerd, I was so careful.
非常小心 我只是... 我一直低着头
So careful, I just... I kept my head down,
往前走
and I kept going.
我没有接触任何人 因为我知道一接触的话
I didn't contact anyone, because I knew that if I did,
肯定有人受伤
that someone would get hurt.
所以我马上离开了
That's why I left in the first place.
如果我留下的话 下个受伤的人会是谁?
Who else is going to get hurt because of me if I stay?
他怎么样?
How is he?
他比我前段时间看到的更专注了
He's a lot more focused than I've seen him in a while.
我知道我的离开伤害了他
I know when I left, I hurt him.
也伤害了我自己
It hurt me too.
他有说什么吗?
Did he say anything?
- 我离开之后?  - 关于你的事?
- After I left?  - About you?
- 他什么都没说  - 一次都没有?
- He didn't say anything.  - Not once?
在我们面前没有
Not in front of us.
抱歉 亲爱的
Oh, sorry, darling.
我没时间做晚饭
I didn't have time to make dinner.
委员会延时了
The committee meeting ran late.
给你三次机会猜为什么
Three guesses why.
我保证 那些贵妇们很喜欢这样的星期五酒会
I swear, those ladies love their wine Fridays.
你要点意大利餐吗?
You want to order italian?
听着 我们得聊下
Listen, we need to talk.
怎么了? 一切还好吧?
What's the matter? Is everything okay?
当然好 我只是...
Yes, of course. I just...
我想谢谢你做的一切
I wanted to thank you for everything,
你对我的支持
How you've stood by me.
Mattew 发生什么事了?
Matthew, what's going on?
转右一点
Turn to your right a bit.
什么? 我不懂
What? I don't understand.
伙计们! 你们过来看看
Uh, guys! You need to see this.
如果您是刚刚调到本台 我们正在
If you're just joining us, we are live
联邦调查局副局长Matthew Graham家门外实况转播
outside the residence of FBI deputy director Matthew Graham,
今晚早些时候 Graham的妻子被暗杀了
where earlier tonight an attempt was made on Graham's life.
根据初步报告
According to preliminary reports,
枪弹射入其室内
shots were fired into the home,
Gramham受伤 妻子Sarah身亡
wounding Graham and killing his wife Sarah.
当局还在收集证据
Authorities are still piecing together the evidence,
但一位知情人士透露
but a source close to the investigation
联邦调查局确信
tells us that the FBI believes this to be
这是刺客Nikita Mears的所作所为
the work of assassin Nikita Mears.
我们需要回应
We wanted a response.
- 我们有回应了  - 不 这不对
- We got a response.  - No, this is all wrong.
对于商会来说太高调了
This is too loud for the Shop.
对于Amanda就不高调了
But not for Amanda.
这太过分了 对于她来说也是
This is over the top, even for her.
我们把聚光灯射向Graham
We put the spotlight on Graham.
Amanda就推回给Nikita
Amanda shoved it back to Nikita.
她真强硬
She's really playing hardball.
那现在轮到我们强硬了
Then it's time we did the same.
如果Gramham是复制出来的 我们把他曝光
If Graham is a double, we expose him to the world.
我们没有实质证据
We have no physical proof.
联邦调查局有 他们必须有
The FBI, they have to have a sample
Gramham本人的基因取样 对吧?
of the real Graham's DNA, right?
对
Sure.
全体人员都被要求提供取样的
All personnel are required to provide one.
那我们就可以对比存档上的
Then we have them compare it to what's on file,
和骗子手上的基因取样
to the impostor's DNA.
我认为这个复制人不会和我们合作
I don't think the double is going to cooperate.
那我们就让他别无选择
So we don't give him a choice.
联邦调查局验尸时都要拿基因样本
The FBI has to take a DNA sample while they're doing an autopsy.
你想杀了联邦调查局的副局长?
You want to kill the Deputy Director of the FBI?
Amanda已经杀了
Amanda already did that.
她不是想让大家认为我就是杀手吗?
She wants the world to see me as an assassin?
那就随她意吧
Let's give her what she wants.
Gramham藏在他家里
Graham's holed up at his casa.
毫无疑问 安全系统也加倍了
Not surprisingly, the security detail has doubled,
那里媒体的人也很多
as has the media presence.
接近他家会非常困难
Getting close is gonna be insanely hard.
要接近而且不被发现 就更没可能了
Getting close without being seen, forget about it.
我们现在资源有限
Standard kill protocols won't work,
标准的刺杀计划肯定没用
not with our limited resources.
我们来玩声东击西吧
We're gonna have to run a bluff.
逼他出来 或者至少
Get him out of there, or at least,
让他想离开那
get him to want to come out of there.
这需要双人操作才行得通
This only works as a two-man op.
我们这样可以吗?
Are we okay with that?
可以 绝对可以
Yeah, absolutely.
谢谢你的帮助
Well, thanks for your help.
如果你认为我会留下
If you think I'm leaving here
扫描器就走 那你错了
without that scanner, you're wrong.
你带不走扫描器的
Not gonna happen.
不打就带不走?
Without a fight?
听着 我们连里面是什么都不知道 对吧?
Look, we don't even know what's on that thing, right?
我提议先打开看看 再决定
I say we crack it first, decide then.
我们有新发现后会通知你的
I'll contact you when we find something.
我不会让你或者扫描器离开我的视线
Uh... uh, I'm not letting you or it out of my sight.
另外 你一直和
Besides, you keep mixing it up
仓库那些小伙子们混在一起
with boys like that at the warehouse,
- 你迟早会需要我的  - 需要你?
- you are gonna need me.  - Need you?
就像暴动时组织需要你那样?
The way we needed you at division during the mutiny?
别说需要了 你拿枪指着
Instead of backing us up, you put a gun
Birkhoff的头 还想开枪射Michael
to Birkhoff's head, and you tried to shoot Michael.
容我澄清下 是Michael先动手的
In my defense, it was Michael.
好 听着
Okay, look, look.
我一直在回想你说过的话
I've been thinking about what you said.
在多伦多的时候
Back in Toronto?
别做傻事
Don't do this.
你作为Owen的那段生活肯定有意义
Your time as Owen has to mean something.
对 意味着我失去了10年的生命
Yeah, it means I lost ten years of my life.
并不只有损失
It wasn't just a loss.
你也有收获 我们这些朋友
You gained as well. All of us.
我们都在乎你
We care about you.
我... 我确实射了黑盒
I... I did shoot the Black Box.
我不是你的敌人
I'm not your enemy.
也许我们可以互相帮助
Maybe we could help each other out.
你可以待到Sonya破解了那个扫描器
You can stick around until Sonya decrypts the scanner.
之后的事情我可不能保证
After that, no promises.
像Nikita Mears这样的刺客以为消灭了证人
Thugs like Nikita Mears think that by killing the messenger,
就消灭了证据
they kill the message.
相反 这只会让真相更快水落石出
Instead, it just makes the truth even louder.
我现在可以确认Nikita Mears
I can now confirm that the secret Cayman account
在也门的秘密账户
in Nikita Mears's name was,
其实是巴基斯坦情报局设立的
in fact, funded by Pakistani intelligence.
追查这条线索
Now, tracing this connection
并不容易 因为这些资金
has not been easy because the money
是通过一个关键的第三方势力小心转移的
was carefully laundered through a key third party,
此时此刻我们正在追查这个第三方势力
a party that we are closing in on as we speak.
他们想把事态做的像Nikita
They want it to look like Nikita
在为巴基斯坦工作一样
is working for the Pakistanis.
- 为什么?  - 如果他们能够
- Why?  - If they can prove
证实巴政府是
the Pakistani government was
刺杀总统的幕后主使
behind the President's assassination,
美国就可以名正言顺的入侵
then the U.S. would have grounds to invade.
证实? 我们可是美国
Prove? This is America.
只需要有个暗示 模糊的暗示就够了
All they have to do is hint, vaguely insinuate.
哦 那么他们是在计划暗示出一次世界大战
Well, then they're planning to hint their way into a world war.
巴基斯坦是核势力国家
Pakistan is a nuclear power.
哦 商会他妈为什么要这样?
Well, why the hell would the Shop want that?
我们只知道
All we know is,
这事情不仅仅是陷害Nikita那么简单
this was always bigger than framing Nikita.
现在我们知道有多严重了
Now we know how much bigger.
那个呢?
What's up with that?
鱼还没有上钩
The shoe yet to drop.
这是Graham第二次使用国安局的情报了
This is the second time Graham has referenced NSA intel.
什么 你觉得他在里边也有内鬼吗?
What, you think he's got a double-in-arms over there?
有可能
Could be.
你能不能黑进联邦调查局的通信记录?
Can you hack into the FBI's communication logs?
查查Graham跟国安局的什么人联系过
Find who Graham has been communicating with at the NSA.
会有不少人的
Gonna be a big list.
你只要使用我们早些的搜索规则
Not if you filter the results
过滤一下就不会太多了
using our earlier search criteria.
只盯着高层的人物就好
Just stick to the higher-level names.
他们想让大众认为Nikita是恐怖分子
They want people to think Nikita is a terrorist.
哦 这样的话 她接下来的行动就像回事了
Well, in that case, they're gonna love what she does next.
我到位了 很快准备好
I'm in position. Be ready soon.
收到 我在停车场
Copy that. I'm in the lot.
你确定是这辆车?
Are you sure the right car is here?
确定
Yep.
五层 黑色SUV
Black SUV, level five.
用雷明顿700(枪支型号)是吗?
Using the Remington 700?
不是 是PSG1型
No, the PSG-1.
稳定性够吗?
Gonna have enough stability with that?
可以 我能搞定
Yeah, I'll be fine.
可是 你很久没开过枪了
Well, you haven't shot in a while.
对 但有些事情是忘不掉的
Well, some things you don't forget.
希望如此
Let's hope not.
Michael 离开你我也悲痛欲绝
Michael, leaving you almost killed me.
不用解释了
Don't have to explain.
那是为了保护你 保护你们
It was to protect you. All of you.
你说得很明白了
Well, you made that clear.
如果我不得不再离开的话 我也会的
If I had to do it over again, I would.
因为你自己做的决定总是正确的
Because your call is always the right call.
- 这些都不是我的决定!  - 不允许别人
- None of this is my call!  - No one else is allowed
- 做决定  - 我不能置你们于险地
- to decide.  - Not if it puts you in danger.
这个被动的局面不是我有意要选择的
This whole impossible situation is not something I chose.
我就不该来这
I shouldn't even be here now.
我还是应该走
I should leave again.
不 你属于这里
No. you belong here.
我们合作会更好一些
We're all better working together.
我们一直是这样
We always have been.
所以你生气是因为我的离开会伤害到团队?
So you're upset I left because it hurt the team?
是的
That's right.
团队需要你 一直是如此
The team needs you. It always has.
我也需要你们大家
I needed all of you too.
我知道
I know.
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
数字化面具快完工了
Digital mask is almost done.
怎么样?
How's it look?
太他妈棒了 我不得不夸自己
Pretty damn good, if I say so myself.
空包弹直接命中
Squib placement was dead-on.
Nikki用假弹打得很逼真
Nikki hit him perfectly with the false round.
我一直在问自己是不是真的
I never cease to amaze myself.
快准备好传送信号了
Almost ready to transmit.
收到
Copy that.
我们会准备好的
We'll be ready.
用点38口径的子弹试试
Try .38s.
弹径更小 更合适
It's a smaller barrel. it'll fit better.
我觉得那打击力量不足
Don't think that's enough stopping power.
我们只有一枪的机会
We're only getting one shot at this.
那就用热装填的空尖弹
Then use hot-loaded hollow points.
热装填 是吧? 你在哪学的那个?
Hot loading, huh? Where'd you learn that?
德州
Texas.
Los Zetas组织的正常训练
It's common practice with Los Zetas.
我在那停留过几周
I spent a couple of weeks with them.
Los Zetas 那可是个强悍的帮会
Los Zetas. That's a rough gang.
没有Michigan Winters那么强悍
Not as rough as Michigan Winters.
也没有成为头号公敌这么强悍
Or seeing that you've become public enemy number one.
是啊 我觉得你在德州的时候我们发现过你
Yeah, I think we got a hit on you in Texas.
为了阻止边境巡逻队发现你的行踪
Birkhoff had a hell of a time keeping
Birkhoff可是花了一段时间的力气
the border patrol from picking up your trail.
很欣慰那个怪才替我打掩护
Well, I'm glad that nerd was watching out for me.
是啊 他是担心你
Yeah. he was worried about you.
必须要谢谢他了
I'll have to thank him.
- 电磁脉冲准备好了  - 发射干扰吧
- E.M.P. is ready.  - Fire the pulse.
嘿 我这没信号了
Hey, I just lost juice here.
没有 我什么都没干 我们还没开始转播
No, I didn't do anything. we weren't even transmitting.
行 好的 我去检查一下天线
Yeah, yeah, I'll go check the cable.
Michael 他回来了
Michael, he's coming back.
又有信号了
We're back.
有一个加密芯片 不过加密法则
It's got a cryptographic chip, but the encryption algorithm
- 是我没见过的  - 好极了
- is like nothing I've seen.  - Great.
我们只能破解源代码了
We're gonna have to unpack the source code.
- 需要多久?  - 哦 如果商会
- How long will that take?  - Well, assuming the Shop
没有用太多黑暗手段的话
didn't protect it with too much dark magic,
- 一两个小时就可以了  - 可以
- A couple hours.  - All right.
这段时间我可以盯住Sam
I can deal with Sam until then.
Sam 别忘了 他可是个演技派
Sam. Don't forget, he's a pod person.
外表看起来可能完全正常
May look all normal on the outside,
不过在内心深处 他很记仇
but deep down inside, he is Sith.
我会注意他的
I'm keeping an eye on him.
而且 他看起来更能自控了
Besides, he does seem more manageable,
更像Owen了一些
more Owen-like.
呦 行了 伙计
Yo, come on, man.
我还需要点时间
I need a little more time.
我跟你说了 我会还你钱的
I told you, I'm gonna pay you back.
你了解我
You know me.
我哪一次没有成功?
Have I ever not come through?
那次不算
That doesn't count.
别 嘿 不要! 别派人来!
No, hey, no! Don't send guys!
我现在就去拿钱
I'm getting the money now.
我是Graham
Graham.
打开新闻看看
Turn on the news.
如果那是副局长Graham
To be that of Deputy Director Graham.
显而易见 他在自己的车旁
You can see, he approaches his car,
而且我们已经证实车辆确实是
and we have confirmed that the make and model of the vehicle
跟Graham所驾驶的一模一样 然后...
is the same one Graham drives. And then...
现在 我再重复一遍
Now, I want to repeat this again.
这段视频来自匿名发布者
This video was provided to us by an anonymous tipster,
我们目前还不能证实
and we have been unable to confirm
这个人 就是 副局长Graham
this is, indeed, Deputy Director Graham.
我们联系了联邦调查局...
We've called the FBI...
你们为什么不封锁这个?
Why didn't you put an end to this?
它直接就播出来了
It just came through,
而且现在已经传到了所有的媒体和网络上
but it's already all over the media and the internet.
召开一个媒体见面会
Call a press conference.
我半个小时之内到办公室
I'll be at the office in half an hour.
等等 我们可以在这发布否定信息
Wait, we could issue a denial from here.
她是在将我们的军! 她想逼我
She's playing mind games! She's trying to get me
躲起来 让我不见天日
to back down, to keep me in a hole.
我要阻止这个 现在就要
I'm putting a stop to this, right now.
这可能正中了Nikita的下怀
That could be exactly what Nikita wants,
让你在事先未安排的情况下出来
to draw you out at an unscheduled time.
她可能会在途中袭击
She might attack during transit.
你说得对
You're right.
没必要冒险 我们可以办到 就在这里
No need to risk it. We can do this, right here.
现在 我再重复一次
Now, I want to repeat this again.
这段视频来自匿名发布者
This video was provided to us by an anonymous tipster.
- 你要干什么 Nikita?  - 我们还不能证实
- What are you doing, Nikita?  - We have been unable to confirm
这个人 就是 副局长Graham
This is, indeed, Deputy Director Graham.
我们联系了联邦调查局
We've called the FBI.
不过被告知他现在不方便接受采访
But were told he's not available at this time.
带一个"B"级的客人来我这
I need one of our guests from level "B" brought up to me,
然后再安排打个电话
and then I need to place a call.
他们来了
There they go.
等等!
Wait!
我们连上了
We're online.
遥控枪状况如何?
Status on the remote gun?
一切正常 我们可以射击了
Green light. we're ready to go.
Alex 有你一个电话
Alex, you've got a call.
是从前台打来的
It's coming from the front desk.
有人从酒店给你打电话
Someone's calling you at the hotel.
喂?
Hello?
引领公众的生活其中有一点好处就是
One good thing about leading such a public life
让你的追随者更容易
is it makes it much easier
找到和联系你
for your fans to find and contact you.
你也是追随者吗?
Is that what you are, Amanda?
- Amanda?  - 我当然是 Alex
- A fan?  - Oh, of course, Alex.
我非常喜欢看你
I've especially enjoyed watching
带领人们 讨伐对抗人口买卖
you lead this crusade against human trafficking.
你要怎么样?
What do you want?
- 注意礼貌 亲爱的  - 哦 抱歉
- Manners, dear.  - Oh, I'm sorry.
我更乐意面对面给你一个更温暖的问候
I'd be happy to give you a much warmer greeting in person.
只要告诉我在哪能找到你就行
Just tell me where I can find you.
那还要等等了
That'll have to wait.
现在 我需要跟Nikita讲话
For now, I need to speak with Nikita.
还蛮着急的
It's rather pressing,
所以我们不要浪费时间了 让Birkhoff给我们联线
so let's stop wasting time, and have Birkhoff connect us.
Seymour 有情况了
Seymour, we have a situation.
你好 副局长 你能告诉我们是怎么回事吗?
Excuse me, Deputy Director. can you tell us what's going on?
- 好了  - 锁定目标
- Here we go.  - Target acquired.
有一段视频 报出我被谋杀了
A video was released, reported to show my death.
这只是彻头彻尾的谎言而已...
This was nothing but an elaborate lie...
Nikki 有电话找你
Nikki, you've got a call in.
这是由刺杀总统的杀手Nikita Mears捏造出来的
Perpetrated by presidential assassin Nikita Mears.
什么?
What?
是Amanda
It's Amanda.
- 只是又一次企图...  - 你好 Nikita
- Just another attempt...  - Hello, Nikita.
我不知道你在哪里 不过我猜
I don't know where you are, but my guess is
你正要杀掉我们的一个重要棋子
you're poised to kill one of our important assets.
- 动摇...  - 猜得很准 Amanda
- Shake...  - Gold star, Amanda.
哦 在你动手之前 有件事情你应该知道
Well, before you do, there's something you should know.
在我们用替身替换目标任务时
When we swap out a target for a double,
我们会留着其本人
we hold on to the original subject
来给我们提供作战保障
to assist in operational support.
Matthew Graham本人就在我旁边
The real Matthew Graham is right here next to me.
如果我们的人死了
If our asset dies, there's no reason
那他本人也就没用了
to keep the original alive.
你明白我的意思吧 Nikita?
Do you understand what I'm saying, Nikita?
扣动扳机 你也就等于杀了Matthew Graham本人
You pull that trigger, you'll be killing the real Matthew Graham.
这些欺骗 这些骗局
These tricks, these attempts at deception,
正是她个人越来越绝望走投无路的最好说明
are nothing more than signs of an increasingly desperate individual.
我活着...
And I am alive...
一旦发布会结束的话
Once this press conference is over,
我们就杀不了他了 如果真是这样的话
we lose our shot at him, and if that happens,
谁知道他还会怎么作恶?
who knows how much more damage he'll do?
没错 Nikita 不惜一切代价杀了Graham
Yes, Nikita. Stop Graham at all costs.
最多你也就是再背负
All it will require of you
一条无辜的人命
is the death of one more innocent.
反正已经杀了那么多人了
You have so much blood
多死一个又何妨?
on your hands already, what's one more life?
我怎么知道你是不是在吹嘘?
How do I know you're not bluffing?
你或许早已经杀了Graham本人
You could have killed the original graham a long time ago.
告诉她
Tell her.
我是... 我是Matthew Graham
This is... this is Matthew Graham.
- Birkhoff  - 正在查
- Birkhoff.  - On it.
你能告诉我你在哪里吗?
Can you tell me where you are?
我也不知道我在哪里
I have no idea where I am.
- 马上就好 Nikki  - 这群疯子已经
- Incoming, Nikki.  - These lunatics have been
把我困在这里好几个月了 你是谁?
holding me here for months. Who is this?
你现在认真听我说
I need you to listen to me carefully.
现在有另一个人冒充是Matthew Graham
There's another person posing as Matthew Graham.
他掌管的是联邦调查局的特种部队
He's running a task force for the FBI,
所以我要确认你本人的真实身份
so I need to confirm you are who you say you are.
告诉我你进局里之前的最后一个职位是什么吗?
Can you tell me what your last post was before the Bureau?
我是海军负责武器的军官
I was a weapons officer in the navy.
等等 难道这就是他们为何要抓我?
Wait a minute, are you telling me that that's why they took me?
那边到底发生什么事了?
What the hell is going on out there?
Sarah呢?
What about Sarah?
她一定会受不了这种事的
She'd never go along with something like this.
Sarah死了 Matthew
Matthew, Sarah's dead.
- 什么?  - 替身把她害了
- What?  - The double had her killed,
现在他们在把事情忘我身上推
and they're trying to pin it on me.
因为都是你的错
Because it was your fault.
如果你不把信息给联邦调查局
If you hadn't sent that message to the FBI,
她会依然活着 你还是没变啊
she'd still be alive, but as always,
做事从不三思而后行
you never gave a thought
永远不会顾忌你所造成的伤害
to the collateral damage you might cause.
Graham的替身是找到商会的关键 Nikita
Nikita, Graham's double is a key link for the Shop.
是他编造了也门账户和巴基斯坦的关系
He established the Cayman and Pakistan connection,
要是我猜得没错 他给大家引的这条路
and if I'm right, the path he's leading everyone on could lead
会造成更多的伤亡 甚至引起战争
to many more casualties, possibly a war.
好吧 我们来谈下伤亡
Yes, let's talk casualties.
因为你 Dale Gordon死了
Because of you, Dale Gordon is dead.
因为你 Sarah Graham死了
Because of you, Sarah Graham is dead.
我们拭目以待
We'll see.
就回答这些问题吧 我还有...
That's all for questions. I just have...
Nikita 这是我们最后的机会了
Nikita, this is our last chance.
一份声明要宣读一下
One statement that I would like to read.
不管到底是谁在说话
Whoever you are out there,
快开枪杀了那个混蛋!
blow that bastard away!
不管怎样他们都会杀了我的
They're gonna kill me anyway,
要是这个贱人赢了的话 我死也不会瞑目的
and I'll be damned if I let this psycho bitch win,
快开枪! 开枪啊!
So do it! Do it!
Nikita 动手吧
Nikita.
到底还要多少人因你而死?
How many more have to die because of you?
他会造成更多的伤亡的
He'll cause thousands of casualties.
- 快没时间了  - 有一点我们知道
- We're gonna lose him.  - One of the things we know
那就是她是一个冷酷无情的杀手
is that she is a callous and cold-hearted killer,
对人命不会有任何怜惜
with no regard for human life.
她坚信这种残忍代表力量
She believes that such cruelty is a sign of strength.
我跟大家保证 根本不是这样
I am here to tell you that it is precisely the opposite.
我们会找到她 严惩她
She will be found, and she will be punished.
祝贺你 Nikita
Congratulations, Nikita.
你终于除掉了一个
You've managed to eliminate an operative
早就该死了的特工
who had already outlived his usefulness.
你唯一赢得的
All you've succeeded in doing
无非就是再多背负一条无辜的人命
is you've spilled more innocent blood.
我希望她能找到你
I hope she finds you.
我也是
So do I.
必须得这么做
It had to be done.
Amanda是绝对不会让Graham活着离开的
Amanda never would have let Graham out of there alive.
是她杀了那些人 不是你
And she's the one who killed those people, not you.
她只是在跟你玩心理战
She was just playing more of her head games.
谢谢
Thank you.
我都忘了我是多么需要你们
I forgot how much I need you guys.
哦 嘿
Oh, hey.
还有人要跟你说话
Another voice to add to the chorus.
Nikita吗?
Nikita?
嘿 Alex
Hey, Alex.
听到你的声音真开心
It's good to hear your voice.
你怎么样啊?
How are you doing?
我会没事的
I'll get by.
你呢?
How are you?
我听说你去追踪一些人贩子了
I heard you took on some traffickers.
- 情况怎么样?  - 完全在我控制之中
- How'd it go?  - Nothing I couldn't handle.
我还得到了一位老朋友的帮助
And I had some help from an old friend.
老朋友?
Old friend?
Sam在这里
Sam's here.
说他想向Amanda报仇
Says he wants revenge on Amanda
说我们应该合作 一起找到她
and that we should work together to find her.
他帮助我逃离了危险
He helped me out of a jam,
但我依然不确定是否该相信他
but I'm still not sure I can trust him.
Owen啊
Owen.
给他一次机会吧
Give him a chance.
我... 我依然觉得我所认识的他
I... I still think that the person I knew
并没有完全消失
is somewhere inside there.
知道吗 Alex 我觉得我...
You know, Alex, I think I just...
我还是需要相信有些人
I need to believe that there are people
依然值得我们为之战斗 知道吗?
still worth fighting for, you know?
你知道Michael依然关心你的
You know Michael still cares about you.
我知道 我也这么希望
I know, I just hope he does too.
我得挂了 稍后再联系你
I gotta go. I'll check in soon.
嘿 万事小心
Hey, be careful.
趴下 都趴下! 快点!
Get down, get down! Do it now!
不许动! 趴下!
Don't move! Get down!
- 你们抓错人了!  - 我说了 趴下!
- You've got the wrong person!  - I said, get down!
啊!
Aah!
快点 快走!
Come on, move!
- 嘿 嘿 嘿!  - 我们得帮忙...
- Hey, hey, hey!  - We gotta help...
听我说 在这个小地方
Listen to me. we can't do anything
我们什么都做不了! 我们先出去
from inside a cell! Let's clear out,
随后再想办法 但是现在 我们得快点走!
and we can figure it out, but right now, we gotta go!
快走!
Go!
有关当局依然在调查
Authorities are still investigating
Graham的谋杀案件
Graham's shocking murder.
其中他们正在分析的一个难题 就是一段录像
One piece of the puzzle they're analyzing is the video,
这段视频在袭击发生后不久 被人送到了新闻处
sent to news outlets shortly after the attack.
我很抱歉采取这种过激行动
I apologize for taking such a drastic action,
但我杀的这个人
but the man calling himself
并不是Matthew Graham本人
Matthew Graham was not who he said he was.
我非常确定 所以我们做个交易吧
I am so sure of that that I will make this offer.
对他的尸体进行DNA检测
Do a DNA test on his body
跟原有的DNA样本对比
and compare it to the samples already on file.
只要你们这么做 我就自首
Do that, and I will turn myself in.
我们就是想要避免
This is exactly the sort of undue attention
引起这种过度关注
we sought to avoid.
DNA检测 验尸 突发事件等 我们都计划好了
DNA tests, autopsies, contingencies we've planned for.
我们要考虑的是说好的协议
Taking established protocols into account.
不是Nikita这个不稳定的变数
Not the volatile movements of Nikita.
不得不承认
I have to admit,
当她扣动扳机时 我的确是惊讶到了
I was a bit surprised she pulled the trigger.
或许她真的已经变了
Perhaps she really has changed.
嘿 Michael...
Michael...
谢谢你
thank you.
我知道这场战争中 肯定会有伤亡的
I know there are going to be casualties in this war,
但是今天
But today,
因为有了你 我不用自责自己是一个杀手
I didn't have to be a killer because of you.
知道吗 在外面我最不想看到的
You know, the hardest part about being out there
就是那些到处张贴的通缉我的海报
was seeing myself on those wanted posters.
它不断的触动我最深处的恐惧
This constant reminder of my worst fear,
那就是我只是"组织"创造出来的
that all I am is what Division made me.
"组织"不再跟我们有任何关系
Division doesn't define any of us anymore.
我们战斗是因为我们想战斗
We fight because we want to
也因为我们会一直互相扶持
and because we're here for each other.
所以我们是一个团队
That's why we're a team.
Michael 拜托你 能不能不说团队吗?
Michael, can we stop talking about the team, please?
Nikita 我说团队是有原因的
Nikita, there's a reason why I'm talking about the team.
我依然在这里帮你
I'm still here to help you,
永远都会
and I always will.
我依然在跟Amanda和商会斗争
And I'm still here to fight Amanda and the Shop.
但不再是为了我们的将来
But I am done fighting for us.
不管联邦调查局的验尸情况如何
No matter how the FBI autopsy plays out,
这件事已经逼得我们必须要速战速决了
this has already forced us to accelerate our timeline.
揭露Alexandra Udinov作为第三方
Revealing Alexandra Udinov as the third party
给巴基斯坦提供资助 完成暗杀
who helped Pakistan finance the assassination
本不应该是现在就做的
was not supposed to have happened until later.
这真的重要吗?
Does it really matter?
Alex也没法否认她在资助Nikita的事实
It's not like Alex can deny she's funding Nikita.
随便看一下Udinov账户 就会知道她已经资助
A look at the Udinov accounts will show she's been financing
她们那个小团队几个月了
their little band for months.
她们怎么去跟事实争辩呢 是吧?
How are they going to fight the truth, hmm?
我们现在进行的项目
The projects we have under way
相互重叠 相互依赖
are overlapping and interdependent.
所以时机非常重要
That is why timing is so important.
Graham本来还有其他事情要做
Graham had more of a part to play.
那我们就调整
Then we'll adjust.
别忘了 我们手中还有一张王牌
Don't forget, we still have one more ace in the hole,
他的任务才刚刚开始
and his mission is just beginning.
国家安全局 副局长 Ronald Peller
目标可能性: 98.9%
嘿 Birkhoff
Hey, Birkhoff.
国家安全局的搜查怎么样了?
How's the NSA search going?
找到替身了吗?
You find any doppelgangers yet?
还没有 暗影网还在搜索
Not yet, shadowbot's still doing his thing.
可能还需要等等吧
I guess you're just gonna have to wait.
--=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 兜来兜去
时间轴:  sharefans_竺
翻译: 初见 伊娃  sharefans_竺 nikifa
校对: 失眠影 飞天宇